本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  卫老哥
■
・ 翻译  茶炒栗子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  宅女之后
・ 翻译  艾瑞卡
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  幸田实果子
译  天朝直属
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  凭陵新月  兜爹  Sage  阿包  凭陵新月  兜爹  Sage  阿包  凭陵新月  兜爹  Sage  阿包  凭陵新月  兜爹  Sage
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季第十九集
是我的错觉  还是真的越来越难
Is it just me, or is it getting harder
分辨出谁是游客了
to tell these tourists apart?
不喜欢游客吗  肖
Don't appreciate visitors, Shaw?
我不喜欢他们的腰包
I don't appreciate their fanny packs.
太容易藏手榴弹
Pretty handy for concealing a grenade.
出租车
Taxi!
看到号码了  芬奇
Got eyes on our number, Finch.
李奥娜・温赖特
Leona Wainwright,
人事管理局助理文员
clerical assistant in the Office of Personnel Management.
人管局的职权从背景考核一直
The OPM manages everything from background checks
管到退休津贴
to pension benefits.
联邦部门  这么说李奥娜住华盛顿特区
Federal. So Leona lives in D.C.
她是来城里看百老汇表演的
She's in town to see a Broadway show.
所以你就要我们穿成这样  哈罗德
Is that why you had us dress up, Harold?
剧场之夜
An evening at the theater?
敞开心怀  肖女士
You keep an open mind, Ms. Shaw,
也许你会很喜欢呢
you might actually enjoy yourself.
什么剧目
What's the show?
《妈妈咪呀》
Mamma mia.
这次轮到谁了
Whose turn is it to save this one?
掷币决定
Let's flip for it.
人头
Heads.
看来是轮到你了
Guess it's your turn.
李奥娜的出租车还没动
Leona's cab hasn't moved.
车牌号码2X03
Medallion number two, x-ray, zero, three.
注册人是桑吉夫・沃玛
That number is registered to a Mr. Sanjeev Verma.
看起来可真不像桑吉夫
Doesn't look like a Sanjeev to me.
Sanjeev Verma是印度名
肖  需要你帮把手
Shaw, gonna need your help now.
说出名字
Say the name.
肖  出租车司机的电话
Shaw, cabbie's phone.
里瑟先生  李奥娜呢
Mr. Reese? Where's Leona?
对不起  芬奇
Sorry, Finch.
你们不可能预测到
Neither of you could have predicted
对温赖特女士的行动
that the threat to Ms. Wainwright
如此  突然
was so...immediate.
你们拿回的移动电话昨天刚激活
The cellular phone you retrieved was activated yesterday.
注册人是乔纳森・普洛曼二世
It was registered to one Jonathan Plowman, Junior.
应该不是那出租车司机的真名
I'm guessing that's not the cabbie's real name.
没错  乔纳森・普洛曼二世可不开出租车
Correct. Jonathan Plowman, Junior did not drive a taxi.
他是美国革命战争期间美方的间谍
He was a spy for the Americans in the Revolutionary War.
这么说是"时刻警惕"杀了李奥娜
So Vigilance killed Leona.
李奥娜会掌握什么"时刻警惕"想知道的消息呢
What information could Leona have that Vigilance wanted?
温赖特女士为政府工作
Ms. Wainwright worked for the government,
而"时刻警惕"誓言要阻止
and Vigilance has sworn to end
政府对隐私的侵犯
the government's abuse of privacy.
恐怕事关机器
I'm afraid this is about the machine.
我刚到犯罪现场
I just got to the crime scene,
可不只我一个人  联调局的也来凑热闹了
and I'm not the only one. Feds decided to drop by too.
你的魅力肯定能征服他们  莱奈尔
I'm sure you'll charm them, Lionel.
试过了
I already tried.
那群西装笔挺的根本不许我碰他们的调查
These suits aren't letting me within a mile of their investigation.
奥古斯塔・金  联邦调查局的
Augusta King, Federal Bureau of Investigation.
饶了哥吧
Give me a break.
莱奈尔  你可不会想跟联邦特工过不去
Lionel, you don't want to be uncooperative with a federal agent.
你介入了  那我可不想搅进去
You're involved? I don't want nothin' to do with this.
晚了
Too late.
李奥娜・温赖特
One of Leona Wainwright's
在人事管理局的责任之一就是
many responsibilities in the Office of Personnel Management
[批准参加秘密工作]忠诚审查
was security clearances.
忠诚审查
Security clearances?
-审查什么项目  -她还没告诉我
- What for? - She hasn't told me yet.
总之  你要小心
Either way, you need to be careful.
行  没问题
Yeah, no problem.
哥火速滚远
I'm gettin' the hell outta here.
纽约
华盛顿特区
国防       部长
参议员  很高兴见到您
Senator...it's so good to see you.
国防部长没想到您会
The SECDEF wasn't expecting you--
我不是来见他的
I'm not here to see him.
加里森参议员
Senator Garrison.
我想你不是来讨论国防部预算的  要茶么
I don't expect you're here to discuss the D.O.D.'s budget. Tea?
你应该听说了那名女士
I'm assuming you've heard about the woman
横死纽约
who died a very theatrical death in New York.
隐私恐怖分子
Privacy terrorists.
他们自称"时刻警惕"
They call themselves "Vigilance."
他们喜欢如此作态
They do like to make a statement.
知道他们的名字吗
Do they have our names?
组织受到威胁了吗
Has the program been compromised?
有可能  不过要确定这点
It's possible, but I won't know for sure
我们必须有权限进入李奥娜・温赖特的办公室
until we get access to Leona Wainwright's office.
要是有人发现了系统
If anyone finds out about the system...
不会的
They won't.
你凭什么确定
How can you be so sure?
你数月前就丢失了那东西
You lost the thing months ago.
需要我提醒你
Need I remind you
北极光阻止了多少起恐怖袭击吗
of the number of terrorist acts that Northern Lights has prevented?
我们都很清楚
I think we both know
你和你手下的国会议员
that you and your fellow congressmen
要是再遇着一次本土袭击  就全要滚去二流大学
would all be giving guest lectures in second-tier universities
当客座教授了
if another attack happened on our soil.
所以你何不
So why don't you
帮大家个忙
do everybody a favor
把这责任交给我来担
and just leave the heavy lifting to me,
一切照旧
like you always do?
你所谓的"责任"  就是派你的打手
By heavy lifting, you mean sending your goons
非法秘密搜查那名女士的办公室
and their black bags into that woman's office?
你想要我回答这个问题吗
Do you want me to answer that?
联调局已经介入了
The feds are already involved,
那要走官方渠道
which means we need to go through official channels.
此事查到我们头上
If this comes back on us,
我们连坐牢的份儿都没有
prison will be the least of our worries.
派我们周末度假去
Sending us on a weekend getaway?
我们有新号码了
We have a new number.
马修・里德
Matthew Reed,
曼哈顿地区检察官办公室的刑事检察官
criminal prosecutor in the Manhattan District Attorney's Office.
刑事检察官怎么会跟"时刻警惕"扯上关系
How's a criminal prosecutor connected to Vigilance?
没关系  据我所知没有
He's not, as far as I can tell.
那我们干嘛要去[纽约州]韦斯切斯特
So why are we going to Westchester?
因为里德先生周末要去那边
Because Mr. Reed will be spending the weekend there,
所以你和肖女士也要去
as will you and Ms. Shaw.
你们的身份
Your covers.
肖女士是皇后区的贝蒂・哈里斯
Ms. Shaw will be Betty Harris of Queens,
至于你  里瑟先生
And you, Mr. Reese,
是威斯康辛州肯诺沙市的弗兰克・美世
will be Frank Mercer of Kenosha, Wisconsin.
我们不应该去查下
Shouldn't we be looking into
李奥娜给了"时刻警惕"什么消息吗
what information Leona gave to Vigilance?
那个交给我  我会去华盛顿特区
You can leave that to me. I'll be traveling to D.C.
我们未被邀请么
And we're not invited?
我们必须盯紧里德先生
It's important that we not let Mr. Reed out of our sight.
不能再失去号码了
We can't risk losing another number.
弗斯科警探愿意陪我同去
Detective Fusco has offered to accompany me.
派去韦斯切斯特  这是惩罚吗
This trip to Westchester, is this some kind of punishment?
该处是纽约州著名的富人区
装好车了
Got the car packed.
AC/DC乐队还是南方小鸡乐队
AC/DC or the Dixie Chicks?
我看受惩罚的是我
I believe I'm the one being punished.
主体位置查找
里德  马修
皇后区
韦斯切斯特
主体位置找到
曼哈顿的检察官到韦斯切斯特的高中干嘛
What's a Manhattan prosecutor doing at a Westchester high school?
也许来查案
Maybe he's here on a case.
也许不是
Or not.
1994级  欢庆二十周年重聚
欢迎啊欢迎
Welcome. Welcome.
看看哈
Let's see here.
好了
Okay.
弗兰克
Frank.
还有
And...
贝蒂
Betty?
真高兴你来了
So glad you made it.
这周末得多好玩儿啊
Isn't this weekend gonna be so much fun?
东泉高中
1994级  欢庆二十周年重聚
新号码在签到
Our new number is checking in.
真不敢相信芬奇和弗斯科去查"时刻警惕"
I can't believe Finch and Fusco get to track Vigilance
我们却被困在这郊区高中的地狱里了
while we're stuck in suburban-high-school hell.
怎么了  肖
What's the matter, Shaw?
高中时不受欢迎么
Weren't too popular in high school?
我们有更重要的事儿
You know, we have more important things to do
犯不着看着窝囊废
than to baby-sit some loser
在这儿抚今追昔
who just wants to relive his glory days.
马修
Matthew.
-见到你真好  -彼此彼此
- It's great to see you. - You too.
肖  你没事吧
Shaw, you okay?
你一脸古怪
You look strange.
我没事
I'm fine.
马上黑入这家伙的手机
Just gonna bluejack this guy.
贝蒂
Betty?
你能来真是惊喜
I'm surprised you made it.
谁会想错过这一切呢
Who'd want to miss all this?
是啊  没人像你一样耀眼
Yeah, well, no one who looks as good as you.
晚上见
I'll see you tonight.
看来新号码被你吸引了
Looks like you caught our new number's eye.
你想多了
You're reading into it.
给你日程表
Your itineraries.
今晚保龄球馆有酒喝
So there's drinks at the Bowling Alley tonight,
当然了  还有明天的盛大舞会
And, of course, the big shindig tomorrow.
希望你带舞鞋来了
I hope you brought your dancing shoes.
你还跳摇摆舞  是吧
You do still swing dance, don't you?
我可不想显摆
I don't like to show off.
当然了  道格负责餐饮
And, of course, Doug will be catering.
道格・赫米尔
Doug Hemmill.
有点宅
A little geeky.
曾被票选为最佳聆听者
Voted best listener.
对了  道格  开了家餐饮公司
Right, Doug, with the catering company.
道格狗狗秀
Doug's Dog Show.
小型的美食热狗合资公司
It's a little gourmet hot dog joint.
恕我失陪下
If you'll excuse me.
你还真有点像弗兰克
You actually kinda looked like Frank.
看哈罗德给我搞的如何
Let's see how Harold did with me.
也许芬奇是一时笔误
Maybe Finch made a clerical error.
贝蒂・哈里斯
Betty Harris?
我在你心中就长这模样吗  哈罗德
I actually look like this to you, Harold?
不怪我
Not to me.
我运行了一个面部轮廓算法
I implemented a facial-symmetry algorithm
查找跟你和里瑟先生最匹配的
to find the closest match for both you and Mr. Reese.
要是拿掉眼镜和牙套
If you take away the spectacles and the braces,
把卷发拉直
tame the permanent wave a bit,
我相信你和贝蒂・哈里斯
I do believe that you and Betty Harris
还是颇为相
look a great deal--
哈罗德  住嘴  马上住嘴
Harold, stop, right now.
哈里斯女士厌恶高中
Look, Ms. Harris despised high school.
她的博客中列举出了
She keeps a blog enumerating the reasons
她不会去二十周年重聚上出丑的原因
that she wouldn't be caught dead at her 20-year reunion,
因此可以判断她不会去出席
so it's a fair assumption that she would not show.
我是专职博客写手
I'm a professional blogger?
不  博客只是副业
No, the blog is just a side project.
你是牙科保健员
You're a dental hygienist.
芬奇  你知道我精通摇摆舞吗
Finch, did you know I'm a great swing dancer?
你还是威斯康辛州肯诺沙市的床垫大王
And you're the Mattress King of Kenosha, Wisconsin.
我送了真弗兰克免费的[加勒比]阿鲁巴岛之旅
I sent the real Frank on an all-expenses-paid vacation to Aruba,
所以你们俩的身份安排妥当
so the two of you should be all set.
快速保龄球馆
没看到马修・里德
No sign of Matthew Reed.
只有一堆的厚毛衣加啤酒肚
Just bulky sweaters and beer guts.
她看起来挺友好
She looks friendly.
问问她吧
Let's ask her.
打扰一下  你有没有看到马
Excuse me. Have you seen Mat--
我是不是说错什么了
Was it something I said?
你有一整个周末慢慢儿琢磨
You got the whole weekend to find out.
贝蒂・哈里斯
Betty Harris.
真吃惊我居然还能认出你
I'm surprised I even recognized you.
同吃惊
Me too.
杰克  杰克・坦纳
Jack. Jack Tanner.
我穿这身制服你可能不太能认出我
You probably don't recognize me in this uniform.
我还有配枪呢  要看吗
They even gave me a gun. You wanna see?
再说吧
Maybe later.
有的人会比较怕枪
Some people are gun-shy.
弗兰克  看来你还不错
Frank, you're holdin' up pretty good.
还以为离婚对你打击不轻
Expected your divorces to take a toll.
我们应该去跟马修・里德打声招呼
We should really say hi to Matthew Reed.
是啊  他怎么样
Yeah. How's he been?
-你看到他了吗  -坦白说
- Have you seen him? - Truthfully?
都没想到他会来
No one expected him to show.
他一毕业就没回来过了
He hasn't been back since graduation day.
也不能怪他  想想那种情况
Can't blame him, considering the circumstances.
那事儿
You know, the thing?
The thing with the--
女朋友
Girlfriend.
94级       铭记
克莱尔・克雷恩
"Claire Klein."
马修的女朋友高三去世
Matthew's girlfriend died senior year.
是啊  在马修的车上发现她的尸体
Yeah, they found her body in Matthew's car.
记得吗  人们都说他跟她的死有关
Remember? People said he had something to do with her death.
失陪了  我去跟道格打声招呼
Excuse me, I'm gonna go say hi to Doug.
不不不  加黄芥末  只有醋的味道
No, no, no, you see, with yellow mustard, all you're tasting is vinegar.
但加第戎芥末酱  就有种勃艮第葡萄酒的味道
But with dijon, there's, like, hints of burgundy.
这是我第三次因为有货被逮着了
So it's the third time I've been caught with the stuff.
律师在那儿呢
There's our lawyer now.
我有张处方  治疗青光眼之类的
I had a doctor's note for, like, glaucoma or something.
这个人是全曼哈顿最擅长医用大麻案辩护的
This guy does the best medical marijuana defense in Manhattan.
好的
Okay.
还是有人喜欢马修啊
Someone likes Matthew.
好像那家伙有眼光似的
Like that guy's a great judge of character.
弗兰克  不是吧
Frank and beans!
例证啊
Case in point.
哥们儿  你一点儿没变
Buddy! You haven't changed.
好像坐着时光机回到了过去
It's like going back in a time machine.
你看起来就跟我们初识那天一样
And you look exactly the same as the day we met.
-想喝杯吗  -晚饭后吧
- Wanna get lit? - Maybe after dinner.
检察官起身了
Prosecutor's on the move.
? I'll be with you,girl
你该待在家里
You should've stayed home.
? like being low
? like being stoned
? I'll be with you,girl
马修至少有一位仇人
Matthew's got at least one enemy.
? like being stoned
弗兰克有两位
And Frank's got two.
纽约
华盛顿特区
人事管理局
弗斯科警探  纽约警察
Detective Fusco, NYPD.
要查看下李奥娜・温赖特的办公室
Gonna need to take a look at Leona Wainwright's office
还有我的法医摄影师
with my forensic photographer.
你们和那些人是一起的吗
Are you with the other men?
警探  真高兴又见到你
Detective. Nice to see you again.
我们要查看下李奥娜的办公室
Yeah, we're gonna need to get a look at Leona's office.
请自便
Help yourself.
归你们了
It's all yours.
为什么联邦探员死盯这案子
Any idea why the feds are all over this case?
我想跟格罗夫斯女士
I imagine it has something to do
给你的信息有关
with the information Ms. Groves gave you.
什么  李奥娜负责的忠诚审查
What, that Leona managed security clearances?
正是  温赖特女士知道所有
Exactly. Ms. Wainwright would have the name
政府官员的姓名  从会计师到参议员
of every government official, from accountants to senators,
有机密信息权限的人她全知道
who could access the confidential information in her department.
物理副本应该在她办公室的保险柜里
The physical copies would've been in her office safe.
刚被联邦探员们拿走了
Which the feds just confiscated.
但电子副本应该存在
But the electronic copies would be located
人管局的安全网络里
on the OPM's secure network.
那你又要拍拍键盘侵入网络了
So you'll do some loud typing while you hack the network?
恐怕还是要下手轻巧些
I'm afraid it's going to require a bit more finesse,
我得找个地方坐下
and I'll need somewhere to sit.
那是得过夜了么
So this just became an overnight?
局里的住宿预算是每晚85刀
The department budget's $85 a night for lodging.
不过我知道个地方  一般按钟点收费
But I got a place -- it usually rents by the hour,
不过管理员能给我优惠
but the manager gives me a deal.
我还是比较希望别住钟点房
You know, I'd prefer accommodations that don't charge by the hour.
容我来支付你的食宿费用吧
Perhaps you would allow me to bolster your per diem.
-拜托  -好啊
- Please. - All right.
看到马修了
Got Matthew in sight.
你看到之前道格和马修那出了吗
Did you see that thing between Doug and Matthew earlier?
道格还在为克莱尔的事生气
Doug's still pissed about Claire.
马修的女朋友吗
Matthew's girlfriend?
马修是她男朋友  道格是她的蓝颜知己
Matthew was her man, but Doug was her ducky.
她的亲密伙伴  她的柏拉图至友
Her sidekick. Her best platonic friend.
但他追克莱尔根本没戏
But he never had a chance with Claire.
马修后来变了
Matthew was never the same afterwards.
他变了  是因为她的死因吗
He changed because of how she died?
别信那些谣言  哥们儿
Don't believe those rumors, man.
没有什么谋杀
There was no foul play.
马修没杀克莱尔
Matthew didn't kill Claire.
她嗑药过量了  就这么简单
She overdosed, plain and simple.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
菲尔
"Phil."
一晃二十年了
Been pretty baked for 20 years.
都认不出你哪位了
But who the hell are you?
别担心  我都不记得自己哪位了
No worries. I forget who I am myself.
莱奈尔  帮我调一份
Lionel, gonna need you to pull a copy
1994年韦斯切斯特的警方报告
of a 1994 police report from Westchester.
我猜猜  你打算
Let me guess, you're gonna--
独家消息  为什么这些女人酷爱你  弗兰克
Got the scoop on why all these women are so fond of you, Frank.
你向褐色女郎求了婚
You gave the brunette a promise ring,
然后睡了她的闺蜜  红发女郎
then slept with her best friend the redhead
然后又上了那金发女郎
before having a fling with the blonde...
也不算太糟糕
That's not too bad.
还勾搭了人家母亲
whose mother you seduced.
这是什么
What is it?
铭记之夜
看来还是有人认为马修杀了克莱尔
Looks like someone still believes Matthew killed Claire.
铭记之夜刚变成了复仇之夜
A night to remember just turned into a night for revenge.
真不敢相信我丢了车钥匙
Can't believe I lost my car keys.
谢谢你载我一程
Thanks for the ride.
没见其他人要帮你
Didn't see anyone else offer.
见怪不怪了
I'm not surprised.
看来道格不希望你来
It seems like Doug doesn't want you here.
不只是他
Not the only one.
想谈谈吗
Do you wanna talk about it?
算了  我不想沉湎于过去  所以
No, I don't dwell on the past, so...
我到了
This is me.
真巧  我住你隔壁
What a coincidence. I'm right next door.
是啊  真是巧啊
Oh, yeah. That is a coincidence.
-是啊  -真幸运
- Yeah. - Lucky one.
晚安  贝蒂
All right, good night, Betty.
晚安
Good night.
这间有人了
Room's occupied.
紧急疏散
This is an emergency evacuation.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
有臭虫  你被换到304房了
Bed bugs. You're now in room 304.
自己开间房去
Get your own room.
没空房了
No vacancy.
说是有臭虫
Something about a bed bug scare.
忘带浴袍了吗  肖
Did you forget your robe, Shaw?
前线阵地享受不了单人浴
Forward operating bases don't have the luxury of single-sex showers.
你有意见  就跟臭虫睡去
You got a problem with me, you can bed down with the bed bugs.
我监听道格了
I've got ears on Doug.
你盯到他离开聚会了吗
You keep an eye on him till he left the party?
他直接回家了
He went straight home.
一张床
One bed.
地板还舒服些
Floor's better anyway.
同意
Agreed.
马修在隔壁吗
Matthew next door?
正准备监视他  还是先卸行李好了
Was just about to have eyes on him. Thought I'd unpack first.
好主意
Good idea.
弗斯科发来警方报告了
Fusco came through with the police report.
克莱尔・凯文的死因被定性为
Claire Klein's death was ruled
氢可酮服用意外过量
an accidental overdose from hydrocodone.
道格看到马修和克莱尔当晚一起离开
Doug saw Matthew leave with Claire that night,
但是马修告诉警方他们舞会之后发生争执
but Matthew told police they got into a fight after prom.
她很不开心  开走了他的车
She got upset, took his car,
马修称之后再也没看到她了
and Matthew claims he never saw her again after that.
但道格不相信
But Doug doesn't believe his story.
据马修说  不只是道格
According to Matthew, Doug's not the only one.
还有谁会想报复
So who else is out for revenge?
好久没这么轻松过了
I haven't felt this rested in a long time.
但愿如此  警探
I should hope so, Detective.
都过下午一点了
It's past 1:00 in the afternoon.
这些是什么
What's all this?
我还以为你要黑进人管局的网络
I thought you were gonna hack into OPM's secure network.
黑进去了
I did.
所有温赖特女士做过的
Any and all information relating to Ms. Wainwright's role
忠诚审查工作都被清除了
as security clearance manager has been wiped clean.
-联调局干的吗  -深表怀疑
- By the feds? - Doubtful.
更像是被政府高层清除的
Most likely by high-ranking government officials.
便携式X光仪
Portable package x-ray?
这是干嘛  要查管状炸弹吗
What are you, gonna inspect some pipe bombs?
绝大多数先进保险柜都会有铅层
Most modern safes come equipped with a lead shield.
不过  政府疏于设备的更新换代
However, the government has been remiss in updating their equipment.
把这个仪器放在保险柜门上
By placing this device on the safe's door,
我转动转盘时能看到保险柜的内部结构
I can see the safe's internal mechanisms while I turn the dial.
等等  你要撬保险柜
Wait, now you wanna crack the safe?
不只是保险柜  警探
Not just the safe, Detective.
首先  我们得潜进联调局的证据库
First, we have to break into the FBI's evidence lockup.
然后我们再撬保险柜
Then we crack the safe.
跟你混就没有过容易事儿  芬奇
'cause nothing's ever easy with you, Finch.
那  什么时候开工
So... when do we get started?
我从不参加同学重聚是有原因的
There's a reason I never went to a reunion.
就是这
This.
看到热狗鉴赏家了
Got eyes on our hot dog connoisseur.
这是有机芥末籽
It's organic mustard seed,
都是国外进口的  比如加拿大
imported from exotic places like--like Canada.
我会确保道格伤不到马修
I'll make sure Doug steers clear of Matthew.
你去找我们最爱的检察官
You find our favorite prosecutor.
贝蒂・哈里斯
Betty Harris?
你被捕了
I am putting you under arrest...
罪名是偷走了我的心
for stealing my heart.
坦纳
Tanner.
自求多福吧
You're on your own.
得有人拦着我别宰了他
Someone has to stop me from murdering him.
想跳舞吗
Wanna dance?
就怕你不问啊
I thought you'd never ask.
小心  希望监管人不会抓到我们
Watch out, hope the chaperones don't catch us.
或许我们会一起被留堂
Maybe we'll get detention together.
? I wanna hold
? The hand inside you
要不是特别了解你
If I didn't know better,
我会觉得你挺享受啊  肖
I'd say you're enjoying yourself, Shaw.
有个愿意对方领舞的舞伴真不错
It's nice to have a partner who's willing to let you lead.
你的秘密是什么  贝蒂
What's your secret, Betty?
你知道我听过多少的证言吗
You know how many hours of testimony I've heard?
我能看穿别人说没说真话
I can always tell when somebody's not telling the truth.
你比我们其他人看起来年轻十岁
You look ten years younger than the rest of us.
你是怎么处理压力的
How do you handle stress?
时不时的
Every once in a while,
开枪突突人
I shoot someone.
听起来你需要个好律师
Sounds like you need a good lawyer.
不过  我很确定
Then again, I'm sure you're...
你能凭一张嘴就脱身
you can talk your way out of almost anything.
真有意思
You know, that's funny.
我记忆中的贝蒂・哈里斯
The Betty Harris I remember,
她很  内向
she was... a shy introvert.
都不敢跟别人说话
She couldn't even carry a conversation.
你不是贝蒂
You're not Betty.
你是谁
So who are you?
我或许是这里唯一认为你清白的人
I may be the one person here who thinks you're innocent.
? With what's not there
所有人都认为我杀了克莱尔
Everyone knows I killed Claire.
你为什么不
What makes you so different?
我接触过很多杀手
I've spent a lot of time with killers.
我认为你在乎克莱尔
I think you cared for Claire,
但我也认为你有所隐瞒
but I also think that you're hiding something.
不如你告诉我真相
So why don't you just tell me the truth
省得我严刑拷打
so I don't have to beat it out of you?
? Strange you never knew
? Fade into you
"克莱尔"
"Claire"?
什么变态会做出这种事
What kind of psycho would do this?
有人想逼马修崩溃
Someone's trying to drive Matthew to the brink.
你看见道格了吗
You got eyes on Doug?
你觉得是他放的假人
You think he planted the dummy?
他一晚上没有动过
He hasn't moved an inch all night.
图克
Toke.
你有没有看到什么行为古怪的人
You seen anyone acting weird?
你开玩笑吗  所有人都跟以前一样
Are you kidding? Everyone's exactly the same.
只是更胖了
Only fatter.
在座的除外
Present company excluded.
还有费尔  那家伙高了三十厘米  长了九十斤肌肉
And Phil, that dude grew a foot and put on 100 pounds of muscle.
他以前很矮小吗
He was smaller?
他在学校戏剧里扮演过"小蒂姆"
He played Tiny Tim in the school play.
里瑟  你发现威胁了吗
Reese. You spot a threat?
不确定  但看来那位费尔可能是个假货
Not sure, but it sounds like our friend Phil might be an impostor.
本次重聚来的都不是本人吗
Isn't anyone at this reunion who they say they are?
他们说你动作很快
They said you were fast.
他们是谁
Who's they?
看来他们错了
Guess they were wrong.
伙计们  你们跟恐怖忍者似的
Dudes, you're both like scary ninjas.
把刀放下  不然我就拗断他的脖子
Drop the cleaver or I break his neck.
这样够快吗
How's that for fast?
谁派你来的  你来这里干什么
Who sent you? Why are you here?
费尔怎么了
What happened to Phil?
他是本土恐怖分子
This was a domestic terrorist
刚吞了氰化物
who ingested cyanide
以避免向我泄露他所在地下组织的信息
to avoid giving me information about his underground operation.
费尔变成恐怖分子了
Phil became a terrorist?
肖
Shaw.
费尔不是94级的学生
Phil wasn't class of '94.
他是"时刻警惕"的人
He's Vigilance.
"时刻警惕"对马修有什么企图
What does Vigilance want with Matthew?
"时刻警惕"不是冲马修来的
Vigilance isn't here for Matthew.
他们是冲我们来的
They're here for us.
要帮忙处理尸体吗
Need help with the body?
费尔被冷冻了
Phil's on ice.
很可惜  马铃薯球就没地方了
Unfortunately, the tater tots are not.
"时刻警惕"怎么找到我们的
How the hell did Vigilance find us in the first place?
我跟你一样一头雾水
Your guess is as good as mine.
费尔来观察我们的行动
Phil was here to see how we work,
直到我们逼他出了手
until we forced his hand.
可能有更多人
There could be more.
很多人
A lot more.
还有个问题  马修不见了
Got another problem. Matthew's disappeared.
我们得查清克莱尔死亡的真相
We need to get to the bottom of Claire's death
以免本次重聚变成报仇之旅
before this reunion becomes a deep-seated revenge tour.
好变态的恶作剧
That is one sick joke.
里瑟  有人偷换了派对礼物
Reese, someone's tampered with the parting gifts.
克莱尔・克雷恩
氢可酮
Hydrocodone.
克莱尔服用过量的药物
Same drug Claire overdosed on.
道格・赫米尔
克隆电话
新消息  来自克莱尔・克雷恩
来化学实验室找我
短信
来自  克莱尔・克雷恩
来化学实验室找我
克莱尔刚从坟墓爬出来找道格了
Claire just reached out and touched Doug from the grave.
我觉得我们也许搞错了
I think we may have gotten this wrong.
被恐吓的不是马修
Matthew's not the one being terrorized.
而是道格
Doug is.
你多快能赶到化学实验室
How fast can you get to the chem lab?
对克莱尔下手后  我无法再面对自我
"I can't go on with my life after what I did to Claire."
道格・赫米尔
这是你写的吗
You wrote this?
我的自杀遗言
My suicide note?
保龄球馆的照片
The photos at the bowling alley.
克莱尔的假人  药片  为什么
Claire's dummy, the pills, why?
还不够明显吗
Isn't it obvious?
你要杀我
You're gonna kill me.
为什么不呢  你杀了克莱尔
Why not? You killed Claire.
来  坐吧
Here, have a seat.
坐下
Sit down.
我怎么会伤害克莱尔
Why would I hurt Claire?
她是我最好的朋友
She was my best friend.
每次你把她弄哭  都是我在陪她
I was always there for her whenever you made her cry.
你陪她是因为你想跟她上床
You were always there 'cause you were trying to get in her pants,
毕业舞会也不例外  道格
and prom night was no exception, Doug,
因为我们一吵完架她就去找你了
'cause she ran straight to you after we fought.
她在舞会上跟你离开后  我再也没见过她
I never saw her again after she left the dance with you.
我们离开是因为她很不开心
We left 'cause she was upset.
她以为我在跟琳达・福尔摩斯调情
She thought I was flirting with Linda Holmes.
不  她以为你在跟芭芭拉・福斯特调情
No, she thought you were flirting with Barbara Foster.
是  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
但你怎么知道我们为什么吵架的
But how would you know what we fought about?
除非是她告诉你的
Unless she told you
因为那天晚上她后来又跑来跟你哭诉了
because she came crying to you later that night?
我  不  马修  我可以解释
I-no, Matthew, I can explain.
为什么你要让克莱尔死
Why you let Claire die?
为什么你要让所有人认为是我杀了她
Or why you let everyone think I killed her?
我不是故意要伤害克莱尔
I didn't mean to hurt Claire.
我觉得要她喜欢我  她最好是
I thought maybe she'd like me more if she was--
-失去知觉  -放松一点
- Unconscious? - Relaxed.
你到底往她的饮料里放了多少氢可酮  道格
Exactly how much hydrocodone did you slip into her drink, Doug?
你是检察官
You're a prosecutor.
你不是应该把我送上法庭吗
Aren't you supposed to be taking me to court?
恐怕法庭不太喜欢
I'm afraid the court won't look favorably
枪口下的告白
on a gunpoint confession.
这不是正义
This isn't justice.
过去二十年
For two decades,
我一直以为是自己把克莱尔逼上了绝路
I believed I pushed Claire over the edge,
她药物过量是因为我
that she OD'd because of me,
直到我收到这份重聚邀请
until I got this reunion invitation
才开始站在检察官的角度
and I started thinking like a prosecutor
而不是男朋友的角度来思考
instead of a boyfriend.
你想要正义吗
You want justice?
我已经因为罪恶感服了二十年的刑
I served a guilty sentence the last 20 years.
枪毙你  让你在接下来的二十年慢慢腐朽
Shooting you and letting you rot for the next 20,
在我看来就是正义  道格
I mean, that sounds like justice to me, Doug.
不能让你这么做
Can't let you do that.
尽管道格罪有应得
As much as Doug here deserves it.
我就知道你不是贝蒂
I knew you weren't Betty.
你不扮杀手了  我就不扮贝蒂了
I'll stop playing Betty if you stop playing a killer.
趴下  趴下
Get down. Get down!
他们是什么人
Who the hell are they?
本土恐怖分子派来杀我和弗兰克的杀手
Domestic terrorists sent to assassinate me and Frank.
抱歉毁了你们的恶魔高中怨憎会
Sorry to ruin your diabolical high school grudge-fest,
不过有可能
but chances are
我们都没法儿活着离开了
none of us are gonna make it outta here alive.
到底怎么回事  我完全糊涂了
What is going on? I'm so confused.
趴下  闭嘴
Stay down and shut up.
提醒我永远别惹你
Remind me never to make you angry.
彼此彼此
Likewise.
折磨道格让他招供
Torturing Doug so he can confess,
然后把他的死布置成自杀
then making his death look like a suicide?
太艺术了
That's plain artistry.
不过  杀戮不是答案
But, uh, killing's not the answer.
杀戮不是答案  你就这么糊弄我吗
Killing's not the answer? That's the best you can do?
我不知道  我杀戮多了
I don't know. I've killed lots of people.
但朋友们一直告诉我那是错的
But my friends keep telling me it's wrong.
不过  我可以杀完人后继续生活
But, look, just because I can live with myself afterwards
不代表你也可以
doesn't mean you can.
把枪给我
Give me your gun.
你说得对  我无法下手杀道格
You're right, you know. I couldn't kill Doug.
我没法扣动扳机
I couldn't pull the trigger.
我不是杀手
I'm not a killer.
枪  枪
The gun, the gun!
算你走运  我是
Lucky for you, I am.
抱歉打搅你了  肖
Sorry to bother you, Shaw.
我这会儿有点忙  根
I'm a little busy here, Root.
我知道你的情况  所以才打给你
I'm aware of your situation. That's why I called--
-道歉  -道什么歉
- To apologize. - Apologize for what?
"时刻警惕"一直更换通信方式
Vigilance keeps changing the way they communicate.
我得泄露点敏感信息
I had to leak some sensitive information
才能找到他们最新的通信方式
in order to find their latest method,
加密无线电信息
which happens to be coded radio messages.
什么敏感信息
What kind of sensitive information?
先容我自辩下
In my defense,
我知道你和那位柔情铁汉能搞定
I knew you and the big lug could handle yourselves.
你把我们的行踪泄露给了"时刻警惕"
You leaked our location to vigilance?
我刚拦截了另一条加密信息
I just intercepted another coded message.
哈罗德有危险了
Harold's about to be in trouble.
得走了
Gotta go.
你好
How you doin'?
弗斯科警探  纽约警察
Detective Fusco, NYPD.
来取温赖特谋杀案的证据
Need to pick up some evidence from the Wainwright homicide.
案件编号多少
What's the case number?
97726.
稍等下
Give me a minute.
祝你撬保险柜顺利
Good luck cracking that safe.
别让那小X光仪辐射出癌症啊
Try not to give yourself cancer with your little x-ray machine.
先生  你没有权限获取证据
Sir, you're not authorized to receive this evidence.
拜托  就让我看一眼行不
Come on, let me get a peek at it, will you?
这案子我上司追得紧
My boss is up my prostate on this one.
规矩又不是我定的
I don't make the rules.
没错  但可以通融下嘛
Yeah, but you can bend them.
我视线被挡住了  肖
I can't get a clean shot, Shaw.
我完全看不清  子弹也没了
I can't get a shot at all. I'm out of ammo.
用烟雾熏出来
Gotta smoke 'em out.
混合起来
Mix these.
拿着  屏住呼吸  别摇晃
Here, hold your breath. And try not to shake it.
还有一颗子弹
I got one left.
好
Okay.
别浪费了
Make it count.
向来讨厌化学
Always hated chemistry.
你搭档呢
Where's your partner?
上厕所了
He went to take a leak.
那哥们膀胱跟小孩儿似的
Guy's got the bladder of a two-year-old.
他马上就回来了
He'll be right back.
我会尽快的  警探
I'm moving as fast as I can, Detective.
这是什么
What's this?
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
顶级机密/需特殊批准
北极光
我已经研究
You know, I've been studying
你和你的同伴们有段时间了
you and your associates for some time.
两位前特工
That's two ex-operatives,
一位纽约警探
an NYPD detective.
抱歉  伙伴  我不得不投降
Sorry, partner. I had to surrender.
否则他们就杀了那警卫
They were gonna kill the guard.
你敢伤害弗斯科警探
If you harm Detective Fusco...
得了
Please.
我们都很清楚你不尚暴力
We both know you're not a man of violence.
你帮助别人
You help people,
帮助会陷入危险处境的人
People who are about to be in a lot of trouble--
克鲁格  斯隆
Kruger, Sloan,
克莱普  温赖特
Claypool, Wainwright.
你在事前
You knew something bad was about to
就已经知道了他们会出事
happen to them before it even happened.
这种不可能
Now, the fact that that's possible
恰好证明了我的猜测
proves something I've speculated:
政府
that the government
有一套秘密系统
has a secret surveillance system
一台每时每刻都在监控我们的机器
that spies on us every hour of every day.
我不是政府人士
I'm not part of the government.
但你在保护这一系统
But you are protecting the system.
我知道那保险柜里边的东西
And I think whatever was in that safe
会给我更多关于这一秘密系统的信息
is gonna give me more information about the secret system.
文件请给我
The documents, please.
科利尔先生
Mr. Collier,
你也许不相信我
you may find this hard to believe,
但我认同你们的目标
but I sympathize with your cause.
但不认同你们的手段
just not your methods.
如果你破坏了这一系统
If you jeopardize this system,
会置所有人于危险之中
you'll be placing all of us at risk.
危险
At risk?
我们已经在战争中了
We're already at war...
国家在全天监控民众
a 24-hour surveillance state
无人机袭击  非常规引渡  网络战争
with drone assassinations, renditions, cyber-warfare.
这是专政  我们一直被蒙在黑暗的鼓里
It's turnkey tyranny, and we're being kept in the dark,
真讽刺  这系统居然叫做"北极光"
Which is ironic, since the system is called "Northern Lights."
我们换个更隐秘的地方
What do you say you and I continue
继续进行道德辩论怎么样
this ethical debate some place a little more private?
恐怕我不会加入你
I'm afraid I won't be joining you.
为什么
And why's that?
抱歉迟到了  哈罗
Sorry I'm late, Harry.
奥古斯塔・金特工
Special Agent Augusta King.
袭击者从后面逃了
Assailant escaped out the back.
好可怕的妞儿
That is one scary chick.
好消息  哈罗德
Good news, Harold.
肖和里瑟活下来了
Shaw and Reese survived.
你该跟他们聊聊
You should talk to them.
芬奇  一切都好吗
Finch. Everything okay?
这要看你对"好"的定义了  肖女士
Depends on your definition of "Okay," Ms. Shaw.
弗斯科警探和我反正还活着
I suppose Detective Fusco and I will live to fight again.
重聚怎么样
How was the reunion?
-爆炸式结局  -过去
- Ended with a bang. - Comin' through.
不  我没想杀克莱尔  我发誓
No, I wasn't trying to kill Claire, I swear.
为什么大家都要改变呢
Why did everybody have to go and change?
怎么  不告别吗
What? No good-bye?
窝囊废才需要告别
Good-byes are for suckers.
我会去下城区做笔录
I-I gotta make a statement downtown.
或许会蹲个一年或二十年
Might spend a year or 20 in jail.
幸亏你认识好律师
Lucky for you, you know a good lawyer.
也许我们之后可以再聚聚
Maybe we could get together after.
姐不碰感情
I don't do relationships.
谁说感情来着
Who said anything about a relationship?
科利尔不见了
Collier's disappeared.
探员找不到他
Agents haven't been able to locate him,
她也找不到
nor has she.
保险柜里有什么
So what was in the safe?
黑色预算报告
A black budget report.
美国情报部门预算
不幸的是  它现在在科利尔手里
Unfortunately, it's in Collier's hands now.
恐怕不止如此  哈罗德
I'm afraid that's not exactly accurate, Harold.
科利尔刚刚发出了另一则加密信息
Collier just sent out another coded message.
"扩散"
"Disseminate."
今日匿名人士发布了一份震惊世人的
A shocking revelation today as an anonymous source
音频截取
新闻报道
搜寻档案
政府机密报告
released a classified government report.
最高机密/需要特殊权限
机密预算款项
该报告揭露了一项涉及
The report revealed black budget items
侵略性监视系统的黑色预算
connected to an invasive surveillance system.
北极光
高层政府官员
High-level government officials,
罗斯・H・加里森  美国国会议员
包括罗斯・加里森参议员  都涉及其中
including Senator Ross Garrison, were named in the report.
参议员  参议员
Senator! Senator!
这个超级监视系统是否存在  参议员
Does this massive surveillance system exist, Senator?
不存在
It does not.
那要如何解释今天新闻里所说的预算
But what about the budget leaked to the press today?
北极光是什么
What is Northern Lights?
我对这一项目一无所知
I have no knowledge of a project by that name.
所以  你是说政府
So you're saying the government
没有监视美国人民
is not spying on the American people?
没有
It is not.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
我的"打手"和"非法秘密搜查"
My goons and their black bags
本可以在这个麻烦公之于众前解决它
could've quashed this problem long before it went public.
我没时间和你互相指责
I don't have time for finger-pointing.
公众只差一步就要知道政府
The public is an ass hair away from learning their government
正在监视他们私生活的方方面面了
is trolling through every inch of their private lives.
终止组织
Terminate the program.
我宁可终止你
I would sooner have you terminated
也不会让国家毫无保护
than leave this country unprotected.
国家会受到保护
The country will be protected,
不过不是用你的机器
just not by your machine.
现在
And right now,
你该问问谁会来保护你了
you should be asking who's going to protect you.
关闭组织
Deactivate the program.
不再运行
We're no longer operational.
关掉
Shut it down.
国家安全相关威胁
疑犯
必须立即行动
绝 密
不想搭莱奈尔的车回去吗
Didn't wanna hitch a ride with Lionel?
既然"时刻警惕"要在华盛顿特区行动
I'm afraid if Vigilance is operating in D.C.,
我也该如此
then so am I.
■
结构重组
首要操作被毁
分配至 第三级操作
发送相关号码
重新指派任务给模拟互动界面
有问题吗  格罗夫斯女士
Is there a problem, Ms. Groves?
得走了  哈罗
Gotta go, Harry.
我的舞伴卡刚刚列满了
My dance card just got full.
女士依次列出同意与对方跳舞的卡片